MEHDI H. MAHMUD

JULY FIRST, 1979



MEHDI.MAHMUD@HOTMAIL.COM M.H.MAHMUD@BHAM.AC.UK



+447511118806



HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/I N/MEHDI-MAHMUD/



HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/MEHDIMA HMUD79



HTTPS://WWW.RESEARCHGATE.N ET/PROFILE/MEHDI-MAHMUD

OBJECTIVE

Experience in software, IT and research. I completed a PhD in Applied Mathematics at the University of Birmingham. I worked as a researcher at the same university and now participating in a 6 month coding bootcamp to become a web developer.

WEB SKILLS

EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH FELLOW/UNIVERSITY OF BIRMINGHAM

Sep 2019- 30th May 2021

Research project: Maximising cavitation to clean dental implants, EPSRC Grant

UNIVERSITY OF BIRMINGHAM

2015-2019

Teaching assistant- part time- during my PhD study.

ASS.LECTURER/ SALLAHADDIN UNI./ERBIL 2009-2014

Assistant lecturer at Mathematics Department / College of Science /Salahaddin University/Erbil/IRAQ.

TEACHING ASS. / SALLAHADDIN UNI./ERBIL 2003-2007

Teaching assistant-Full time- at Mathematics Department / College of Science /Salahaddin University/Erbil/IRAQ.

VIDIO EDITOR/IT

2000-2014

Part time job as IT and video editor at Zagros tv and Gulan TV in Erbil.

EDUCATION

PHD. (2015-2020)

School of Mathematics, University of Birmingham, UK, July 2020.

MICROBUBBLE DYNAMICS NEAR RIGID BOUNDARIES

MSC. (2007-2009)

School of Mathematics, Salahaddin University/Erbil

BSC. (1998-2002)

School of Mathematics, Salahaddin University/Erbil

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

HTML, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript, Git, Node, Express Js

OTHER SKILLS

Microsoft Office, Adobe Premier, Fortran, Matlab

ACADEMIC ADMINISTRATION & SERVICE

- 2013-2015 Member of the Curriculum Development Committee at the Mathematics Departments College of Science /Salahaddin University/Erbil/IRAQ
- 2004-2014, Member of the final examination committee for undergraduate students.
- 2009-2014, Coordinate of the Mathematics Department, College of Science, Salahaddin University-Erbil, IRAQ.

- Advanced Calculus, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Erbil-Iraq., 2012-2014
- Latex Package, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Erbil-Iraq., 2013
- Numerical Analysis, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Erbil-Iraq., 2010, 2014
- Visual Basic programming, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Erbil-Iraq., 2010-2012.
- Visual Basic programming, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Soran-Iraq., 2008-2010.
- Computational Mathematics using Matlab, Mathematics Department, Salahaddin University-Erbil-Iraq, IT Department in Lebanese French University-Erbil, 2013-2007,

RESEARCH INTERACTS

- Bubble dynamics; Modeling Cavitation, Boundary integral method; Numerical Modeling; Computational Fluid Dynamics.
- Abaqus ; Modeling Cavitation around ultrasonic dental scaler.

PUBLICATIONS

- **1.** Wang, Q., Mahmud, M., Cui, J., Smith, W.R. and Walmsley, A.D., 2020. Numerical investigation of bubble dynamics at a corner. *Physics of Fluids*, *32*(5), p.053306.
- **2.** Vyas, N., Mahmud, M., Wang, Q.X. and Walmsley, A.D., 2020. Imaging and Quantification of the Area of Fast-Moving Microbubbles Using a High-Speed Camera and Image Analysis. *JoVE (Journal of Visualized Experiments)*, (163), p.e61509.
- **3.** Rostam K. Saeed and Mehdi H. Mahmud, Solution of a system of two-dimensional linearFredholm integral equation of the second kind by quadrature methods, *Australian Journal of Basic and Applied Sciences*, Vol.3, No.3 (2009), 1701-1715.
- **4.** Mehdi H. Mahmud andRostam K. Saeed , Numerical Solution of System of Two-DimensionalLinear Fredholm Integral Equations of the Second Kind by Adomian Decomposition Method, *Proceeding of the 4th International scientific conference of Salahaddin University-Erbil*,October 18-20, Vol.1 of 4 (2011), 31-34.fa

REFERENCES

- Qianxi Wang: Senior Lecturer at School of Mathematics, University of Birmingham, Birmingham, UK Tel: +44 (0) 121 414 6602, Email: g.x.wang@bham.ac.uk.
- Professor Damien Walmsley: Professor of Restorative Dentistry Tel:+44 (0) 121 466 5493 (Secretary), Email: <u>a.d.walmsley@bham.ac.uk</u>